Life isn't measured in minutes, but in moments.
The Curious Case of Benjamin Button is a drama, fantasy,
romance film directed by David Fincher.
Born under unusual circumstances, Benjamin Button springs into being as an
elderly man in a New Orleans nursing home and ages in reverse.
Twelve years after his birth, he meets Daisy, a child who flits in
and out of his life as she grows up to be a dancer.
Though he has all sorts of unusual adventures over the course of his life, it is his relationship with Daisy,
and the hope that they will come together at the right time, that drives Benjamin forward.
Benjamin Button, played by Brad Pitt.
Daisy Fuller, played by Cate Blanchett.
Queenie, played by Taraji P. Henson.
Caroline Fuller, played by Julia Ormond.
Thomas Button, played by Jason Flemyng.
Elizabeth Abbott, played by Tilda Swinton.
The Curious Case of Benjamin Button is a 2008 American romantic fantasy drama film
directed by David Fincher and adapted by Eric Roth and Robin Swicord from F.
Scott Fitzgerald's 1922 short story.
The film stars Brad Pitt as a man who ages in reverse and Cate
Blanchett as his love interest throughout his life.
The film also stars Taraji P.
Henson, Julia Ormond, Jason Flemyng, Elias Koteas, and Tilda Swinton.
Producer Ray Stark bought the film rights to do the short story in the mid-1980s with Universal Pictures backing the film, but struggled
to get the project off the ground until he sold the rights to producers Kathleen Kennedy and Frank Marshall in the 1990s.
Although it was moved to Paramount Pictures in the 1990s, the film did not enter production
until after Fincher and Pitt signed on along with the rest of the cast in 2005.
Principal photography began in November 2006 and wrapped up in September 2007.
Digital Domain worked on the visual effects of the film, particularly in
the process of the metamorphosis of Pitt's character.
The Curious Case of Benjamin Button was released by Paramount Pictures
in the United States and Canada and by Warner Bros.
Pictures in international markets on December 25, 2008, to positive reviews, with major praise for
Fincher's directing, Pitt's performance, production values, and visual effects.
The film was a box office success, grossing $335.8 million
worldwide against its $150–167 million budget.
The film received a leading 13 Academy Award nominations at the 81st Academy Awards, including Best Picture,
Best Director for Fincher, Best Actor for Pitt, and Best Supporting Actress for Taraji P.
Henson, and won three, for Best Art Direction, Best
Makeup, and Best Visual Effects.
The film explores themes of new york city, navy, funeral, diary, tea.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.